Guide to the Larry Racioppo Photograph Collection 1989-2017 PR 208
New-York Historical Society
Larry Racioppo photograph collection
1989-2017
New-York Historical Society
Racioppo, Larry
PR 208
13.79 Linear feet (10 boxes, 2 oversize folders)
The Larry Racioppo photograph collection spans the period from 1989-2017 and contains approximately 932 color and black and white photographs of New York City taken by Racioppo. The bulk of the collection are images of distressed neighborhoods taken while Racioppo worked as a photographer at the Department of Housing Preservation and Development, and of churches in the five boroughs, some housed in former theaters, synagogues, and storefronts.
Arrangement
The collection is organized by subject in five series:
Series I: New York City after September 11, 2001
Series II: New York City Churches
Series III: New York City Department of Housing Preservation and Development
Series IV: Photographs from The Word on the Street: The Photographs of Larry Racioppo
Series V: Chapbooks
Biographical Note
Larry Racioppo (1947- ) was born in Brooklyn, NY. A New York City-based photographer, his work focuses on the urban landscape. Racioppo had his first solo exhibition in 1977 at Brooklyn's f-stop gallery, and in 1980 published his first book of photographs, Halloween.
Racioppo worked as the official photographer for New York City's Department of Housing Preservation and Development (HPD) from 1989 to 2011. He was hired by HPD to document the city's rebuilding of its distressed neighborhoods, from Bedford Stuyvesant to Harlem to the South Bronx.
When he received a Guggenheim Fellowship in Photography in 1997, Racioppo took a leave from HPD to create a series of panoramic urban landscapes. He returned to HPD to coordinate an exhibition at the Museum of the City of New York documenting the agency's work. While continuing to photograph for HPD, Racioppo had solo exhibitions of two in-depth personal projects: Forgotten Gateway: The Abandoned Buildings of Ellis Island at the National Building Museum, and The Word on The Street at the Museum of Biblical Art.The New-York Historical Society commissioned Racioppo to document St.Paul's Chapel during its use as a relief center after the Sept.11, 2001 terrorist attacks.
Racioppo's work is also held at the Museum of the City of New York, The Brooklyn Museum, the Brooklyn Public Library, El Museo del Barrio, and the National September 11 Memorial & Museum.
Access Restrictions
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Series I: Most of the photographs in this group were either commissioned by the New-York Historical Society or were printed for exhibition purposes. The St. Paul's Chapel and rescue workers images were done by Racioppo on commission from N-YHS (2002). The fireman's funeral image was donated by Racioppo, February 2003. The 2004 rescue images may have been a donation from Racioppo but that is uncertain.
Series II: Gift of Larry Racioppo, 2017 (accession no. PPAC-2017-82).
Series III: Gift of Larry Racioppo, 2017 (accession no. PPAC-2017-88).
Series IV: Gift of Bruce Berman and Lea Russo, 2016 (accession no. PPAC-2016-47).
Series V: Gift of Larry Racioppo, 2017 (accession no. PPAC-2017-82).
Related Materials
Other photographs of September 11, 2001-related topics can be found in the World Trade center Photograph Collection (PR 169), the Irwin Silver Photograph Collection (PR 209) and the Harry Tarzian Photograph Collection (PR 255). Other photographs of churches and apartment buildings can be found throughout photograph collections in the library, particularly the Geographic File (PR 20).
Scope and Contents
The Larry Racioppo photograph collection consists of approximately 932 photographs taken by Racioppo from 1989-2017. The collection includes both black and white and color prints.
Series I: New York City after September 11, 2001 is composed of 35 contact prints from 4 x 5 inch color negatives and 19 photographs. It contains images of the interior and exterior of St. Paul's Chapel during its use as a relief center after the September 11, 2001 terrorist attacks, including memorials on surrounding fences; portraits of the first responders and rescue workers who were employed at Ground Zero and the support staff at St. Paul's Chapel who tended to the workers and others in the area. It also includes images of the interior and exterior of the building housing Rescue Company 2, a New York City Fire Department company in Brooklyn that sustained heavy losses on September 11; and one photograph of the funeral of firefighter John Moran, who died on September 11. Most of these images were commissioned by the New-York Historical Society in the wake of the September 11, 2001 terrorist attacks, or for related exhibitions at the Society in the following years.
Series II: New York City Churches, contains 97 color photographs documenting churches in the five boroughs, many adapted from former theaters, synagogues, and storefronts. Prints are in four sizes (in inches): 8 x 10, 11 x 14, 11 x 17, and 20 x 24.
Series III: New York City Department of Housing Preservation and Development is composed of approximately 765 photographs taken while Racioppo worked as the official photographer for New York City's Department of Housing Preservation and Development (HPD). He was hired by HPD in 1989 to document the city's rebuilding of its distressed neighborhoods, from Bedford Stuyvesant to Harlem to the South Bronx. The subjects of these photos include demolition, construction, and before and after images of rehabilitated apartment buildings and playgrounds. There are also portraits of tenants in their apartments, squatters, homeless people, building managers, building superintendents, construction workers, HPD staff and program participants, and city and state officials such as Mayor Edward Koch, Mayor Rudolph Giuliani, and Governor Mario Cuomo. This series also contains photos of dilapidated buildings (interior and exterior), unsafe living conditions, evictions, crack house interiors, drug paraphernalia, and graffiti.
Series IV: Photographs from The Word on the Street: The Photographs of Larry Racioppo, contains 16 chromogenic dye coupler prints documenting vernacular displays of religious iconography around New York City. The prints are signed, titled and dated on recto by the photographer. The images were published in the exhibition catalogue produced by the Museum of Biblical Art to accompany The Word on the Street: The Photographs of Larry Racioppo (June 15-August 20, 2006).
Series V: Chapbooks, contains 4 self-published booklets of Racioppo's work.
Color photographs.; Photographic prints.; Portraits.; Church buildings -- New York (State) -- New York -- Photographs.; Disaster relief -- New York (State) -- New York -- Photographs.; Housing.; Rescue work -- New York (State) -- New York -- Photographs.; September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001 -- Photographs.; Bronx (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn (N.Y.); New York (N.Y.); New York (N.Y.) -- Buildings, structures, etc. -- Design and construction.; New York (N.Y.) -- Buildings, structures, etc. -- Pictorial works.; New York (N.Y.) -- Social conditions -- 20th century -- Photographs.; Queens (New York, N.Y.); Staten Island (New York, N.Y.); Trinity Church (New York, N.Y.); Trinity Church (New York, N.Y.). St. Paul's Chapel. -- Photographs.
- Series I: New York City after September 11, 2001, 2001-2004; 3.17 Linear feet
  Arrangement
  Series I is arranged by format: contact prints and photographs. The 4x5 contact prints are arranged by numbers assigned by the photographer.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I consists of 35 contact prints from 4 x 5 inch color negatives and 19 photographs. It contains images of the interior and exterior of St. Paul's Chapel during its use as a relief center after the September 11, 2001 terrorist attacks, including memorials on surrounding fences; portraits of the first responders and rescue workers who were employed at Ground Zero and the support staff at St. Paul's Chapel who tended to workers and other visitors. It also includes images of the interior and exterior of the building housing Rescue Company 2, a FDNY company in Brooklyn that sustained heavy losses on September 11; and one photograph of the funeral of firefighter John Moran, who died on September 11. Most of these images were commissioned by the New-York Historical Society in the wake of the September 11, 2001 terrorist attacks, or for related exhibitions at the Society in the following years.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Most of the photographs in this group were either commissioned by the New-York Historical Society or were printed for exhibition purposes. The St. Paul's Chapel and rescue workers images were done by Racioppo on commission from N-YHS (2002). The fireman's funeral image was donated by Racioppo, February 2003. The 2004 rescue images may have been a donation from Racioppo but that is uncertain.
  - Contact Prints, ca. 2001-2002
    - St. Paul's Chapel, exterior, 2002 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - St. Paul's Chapel, interior, 2002 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - Rescue 2, 2004 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5-6)
    - Rescue Workers, 2002 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, 2001-2004
    - Fireman's Funeral, Belle Harbor, 2001 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
      Immediate Source of Acquisition Note
      Gift of the photographer, February 2003.
    - St. Paul's Chapel, interior and exterior, 2002 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
    - Rescue 2, 2004; 0 Linear feet (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
- Series II: New York City Churches, 1998-2017; 1 Linear feet
  97 color photographs documenting churches in the five boroughs of New York City, many adapted from former theaters, synagogues, and storefronts. Prints are in four sizes (in inches): 8 x 10, 11 x 14, 11 x 17, and 20 x 24. A number of these images appear in Racioppo's self-published chapbook Grace: Photographs of NYC Churches, a copy of which may be found in Series V (box 10, folder 4).
  Series II is organized alphabetically by borough (Bronx, Brooklyn, Manhattan, Queens, Staten Island), and then alphabetically by church name.
  Gift of Larry Racioppo, 2017 (accession no. PPAC-2017-82).
  Credit line: Gift of the artist.
  - Bronx | Apostolic Church International Royal Assembly (951 East 163rd Street) [11 x 17], 2008 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bronx | Bronx Temple Seventh Day Adventist Church [former Dollar Savings Bank] (495 Willis Avenue), exterior and interior [11 x 14], 2002 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bronx | Christian Church John 3:16 (864 Westchester Avenue) [11 x 17], 2009 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bronx | Christian Faith Cathedral (1415-31 Ogden Avenue) [11 x 14], 2003 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bronx | Grace Gospel Church (589 East 164th Street) [11 x 17], 2006 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bronx | Holy Cross Baptist Mission Church (821 Jennings Street) [11 x 17], 2006 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bronx | Iglesia Cristiana del Valle (843 East 156th Street) [11 x 17], 2008 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bronx | Iglesia Cristiana Filadelfia (860 East 156th Street) [11 x 17], 2008 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bronx | Iglesia Pentecostal El Cruce del Jordan (341 East 194th Street) [11 x 17], 2008 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bronx | Nazareth Baptist Church (490 East 165th Street) [11 x 17], 2009 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bronx | Pare de Sufrir, Iglesia Universal (490 East 138th Street), exterior and interior [11 x 17 (2)], 2008 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bronx | Peculiar Assembly of Saints International Church (456 East Tremont Avenue) [11 x 17], 2012 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bronx | Upper Room Church of God in Christ (845 East 170th Street) [11 x 17], 2011 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bronx | Yellow Cross Building(?) (612 Union Avenue) [11 x 17], 2008 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bronx | Zion Hill Pentecostal Church (629-631 East 169th Street) [11 x 17], 2006 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 6)
  - Brooklyn | America Come Back to God Evangelistic Church (550 Rockaway Avenue) [11 x 17], 2009 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn | Asemblee Pentecotiste De La Foi Apostolique (96 Fifth Avenue) [11 x 17], 2011 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn | Bethel United Methodist Church (1325 Bedford Avenue) [11 x 17], 2006 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn | Bethesda Baptist Church (1170 Bushwick Avenue), interior after fire [11 x 14 (3)], 1998 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn | Bright Light Baptist Church (1676 Park Place) [11 x 17], 2006 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn | Brooklyn [illegible] Church (62 Fifth Avenue) [11 x 17], 2011 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn | Celestial Church of Christ (168 Liberty Avenue) [11 x 17], 2009 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn | Church of Spiritual Healing (East New York) [11 x 17], 2010 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn | Ebenezer Gospel Tabernacle Christian Mission U.S.A. (470 Throop Avenue), exterior plus cross detail [11 x 17 (2)], 2010 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn | Emanuel Christian Disciples Church (2095 Fulton Street) [11 x 17], 2011 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn | Euclid Baptist Church (315 McKinley Avenue) [11 x 17], 2009 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn | Evening Star (267 Gates Avenue) [11 x 17], 2008 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn | Freedom Hall Church of God, Pentecostal (629 Albany Avenue) [11 x 17], 2006 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn | Friendly Missionary Baptist Church (775 Lexington Avenue) [11 x 17], 2008 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn | Glorious Church of God in Christ (363 Halsey Street) [11 x 17], 2007 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn | Glorious Temple Deliverance Center, C.O.G.I.C. [Church of God in Christ] (625 Sutter Avenue), banner [11 x 17], 2006 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn | Grace (1895 Atlantic Avenue, corner Ralph Avenue), plus detail [8 x 10 & 11 x 17], 1999 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn | Grace Temple Church of God in Christ (651 Decatur Street) [11 x 14], 2003 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn | Greater New Harvest Church of Christ (1078 Park Place at Kingston Avenue) [11 x 17], 2008 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn | Heyward's Temple (186 Stuyvesant Avenue) [11 x 17], 2008 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn | Holiness in the Way Deliverance Tabernacle (2581 Pitkin Avenue) [11 x 17], 2006 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn | Holy Nazarene Holiness Church (78 Rockaway Avenue) [11 x 17], 2008 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn | Holy Sacred Baptist Church (26 Malcolm X Boulevard) [8 x 10], 2003 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn | House of Faith Church of Holiness, C.O.G.I.C. [Church of God in Christ] (401 Saratoga Avenue) [11 x 14], 2002 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn | Iglesia Cristo Misionera [Missionary Church of Christ] (189 Mother Gaston Boulevard) [11 x 17], 2009 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn | Iglesia Metodista Unida de Knickerbocker [Knickerbocker United Methodist Church] (484 Knickerbocker Avenue) [11 x 14], 2003 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn | Iglesia Pentecostal Camino a Jerusalen [sic] (Bushwick Avenue) [11 x 17], 2009 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn | Iglesia Universal del Reino de Dios (47 Fourth Avenue) [11 x 14], 2002 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn | Jesucristo es el Senor Iglesia Universal (678 Broadway) [11 x 17], 2009 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn | Lexington Avenue Church of God (700 Lexington Avenue) [11 x 17], 2009 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn | Love Church of Christ Written in Heaven (464 New Jersey Avenue, East New York) [11 x 17], 2009 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn | Morning Dew Industrious Baptist Church (265 Nostrand Avenue) [11 x 14], 2002 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn | Nazarene Baptist Church (896 DeKalb Avenue) [11 x 17], 2007 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn | Olutunu Cherubim & Seraphim Church, Pentecostal (900 Rockaway Avenue) [11 x 17], 2006 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn | Paradise (417 Marcus Garvey Boulevard) [8 x 10], 2001 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn | Park Slope Christian Tabernacle [Tabernaculo Cristiano de Park Slope] (98 Fifth Avenue) [11 x 17], 2011 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn | Pilgrim's Union Church of God (799 Blake Avenue) [11 x 14], 2002 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn | Pleasant Grove Tabernacle (1927 Fulton Street) [11 x 17], 2008 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn | River of God Christian Center (110 Wolcott Street) [8 x 10 and 11 x 17], 2007, 2008 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn | St. Augustine (236 Wyona Street) [8 x 10], 1999 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn | St. Augustine Episcopal Church (4301 Avenue D) [11 x 17], 2007 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn | St. Timothy Holy Church (139 Amboy Street) [11 x 17], 2008 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
  - Brooklyn | Second Calvary Baptist Church (503 Glenmore Avenue) [11 x 17], 2007 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
  - Brooklyn | South Road Tabernacle Outreach Ministry (753 Lexington Avenue) [11 x 17], 2009 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
  - Brooklyn | United Christian Assembly Church (2401 Atlantic Avenue) [11 x 17], 2008 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
  - Brooklyn | United Holiness Temple of God in Christ (823 DeKalb Avenue) [8 x 10], 2003 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
  - Brooklyn | Upon This Rock I Will Build My Church "Assembly" Pentecostal Church (2560 Pitkin Avenue) [11 x 17], 2006 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
  - Brooklyn | Victory Missionary Baptist Church (244 Howard Avenue) [11 x 17], 2008 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
  - Brooklyn | Williams Temple (493 Ralph Avenue) [11 x 17], 2006 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
  - Manhattan | Asambleas de Iglesia Pentecostal de Jesucristo Elohim (220 East 118th Street) [11 x 17], 2009 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
  - Manhattan | Church of the Meek (305 West 141st Street) [11 x 17], 2009 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
  - Manhattan | First Corinthian Baptist Church [former Regent Theater] (1912 Adam Clayton Powell Jr Boulevard) [11 x 14 (2) & 20 x 24 (1)], 1999 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
  - Manhattan | Iglesia Pentecostal Padre Hijo y Espiritu Santo (2141 Amsterdam Avenue) [11 x 17], 2011 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
  - Manhattan | Mount Olivet Baptist Church [former Temple Israel] (201 Malcolm X Boulevard) [11 x 14 (2) & 20 x 24 (1)], 2004 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
  - Manhattan | St. John A.M.E. (132 West 134th Street), exterior and mural detail [11 x 17 (2)], 2006 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
  - Manhattan | Salvation & Deliverance Church (37 West 116th Street) [11 x 14], 2002 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
  - Manhattan | Second Canaan Baptist Church [former Lenox Theater] (10 Lenox Avenue) [11 x 14 (2) & 20 x 24 (1)], 2004 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
  - Manhattan | 2nd Friendship Baptist Church (215 West 122nd Street) [11 x 17], 2010 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
  - Manhattan | 125th Street Cathedral (230 East 125th Street) [11 x 17], 2010 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
  - Queens | Highway Church of God in Christ (519 Beach 45th Street) [11 x 17], 2006 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 15)
  - Queens | Praise Tabernacle (Sutphin Boulevard) [8 x 10], 1999 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 15)
  - Queens | St. Genevieve (6 Beach 178th Street) [11 x 14], 2009 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 15)
  - Queens | St. Monica (94-20 160th Street), [8 x 10], 1999 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 15)
  - Queens | Tabernacle of Prayer for All People [former Loew's Valencia Theatre] (165-11 Jamaica Avenue), interior [11 x 14], 1998 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 16)
  - Queens | Trinity Baptist Church (111-74 158th Street) [11 x 17], 2007 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 16)
  - Queens | Universal Church of God (10934 Guy R. Brewer Boulevard) [11 x 17], 2008 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 16)
  - Queens | Westminster Presbyterian Church in Cedar Manor (59-11 115th Road) [11 x 17], 2010 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 16)
  - Staten Island | Pare de Sufrir Iglesia Universal del reino de Dios (260 Port Richmond Avenue at Charles Avenue) [11 x 17], 2009 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 17)
  - Unprinted NYC Churches: Brooklyn, Bronx, Manhattan, Queens, S.I., and unknown, 2017 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 1)
    Spiral bound (8.5 x 11) booklet of proof photographs of churches arranged by borough.
- Series III: New York City Department of Housing Preservation and Development Photographs, 1989-2004; 8.59 Linear feet
  This series includes approximately 765 photographs taken while Racioppo worked as the official photographer for New York City's Department of Housing Preservation and Development (HPD). He was hired by HPD in 1989 to document the city's rebuilding of its distressed neighborhoods in all five boroughs. The subjects of these photos include demolition, construction, and before and after images of rehabilitated apartment buildings and playgrounds. There are also portraits of tenants in their apartments, squatters, homeless people, building managers, building superintendents, construction workers, HPD staff and program participants, and city and state officials such as Mayor Edward Koch, Mayor Rudolph Giuliani, and Governor Mario Cuomo. This series also contains many photos of dilapidated buildings (interior and exterior), unsafe living conditions, evictions, crack house interiors, drug paraphernalia, and graffiti.
  Series III is arranged by location and/or subject, and then by size.
  Gift of Larry Racioppo, 2017 (accession no. PPAC-2017-88).
  - Bronx
    - 8x10 photos, 1989-1991, n.d. (Offsite-box 3, Folder 1-6)
    - 16x20 photos, 1989-2004, n.d. (Offsite-box 5, Folder 1-11)
  - Brooklyn
    - 8x10 photos, 1989-2002, n.d. (Offsite-box 3, Folder 7-11)
    - 11x14 photos, 1990-2004, n.d. (Offsite-box 4, Folder 5-8)
    - 16x20 photos, 1989-2004, n.d (Offsite-box 6, Folder 1-9)
  - Manhattan
    - 11x14 photos, 1990-2004, n.d. (Offsite-box 4, Folder 1-3)
    - 8x10 photos, 1989-1992, n.d. (Offsite-box 3, Folder 12-14)
    - 11x14 photos, 1990-2004, n.d. (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9-11)
    - 16x20 photos, 1989-2004, n.d. (Offsite-box 7, Folder 1-7)
  - Queens
    - 16x20 photos, n.d. (Offsite-box 8, Folder 1)
  - Staten Island
    - 16x20 photos, n.d. (Offsite-box 8, Folder 2)
  - Unidentified
    - 8x10 photos, 1989-1991, n.d. (Offsite-box 3, Folder 15-17)
    - 16x20 photos, 1989-2004, n.d. (Offsite-box 8, Folder 3)
  - HPD Staff and Program Participants
    - 8x10 photos, 1989-1992, n.d. (Offsite-box 3, Folder 18)
    - 16x20 photos, 1990-2004, n.d. (Offsite-box 8, Folder 4-6)
- Series IV: Photographs from The Word on the Street: The Photographs of Larry Racioppo, 1990-2005; 2 Linear feet
  16 photographs documenting vernacular displays of religious iconography around New York City. The prints are signed, titled and dated on recto by the photographer. The images were published in the exhibition catalogue produced by the Museum of Biblical Art to accompany The Word on the Street: The Photographs of Larry Racioppo (Jun 15-Aug 20, 2006).
  The photographs include:
  Apartment Door Diptych, West 140th Street near Adam Clayton Powell, 1996, 16x20
  Do you Believe This? Frederick Douglass Boulevard near West 123rd Street, 1992, 16x20; Tin Knocker's Toolbox, Gold Street, Manhattan, 1995, 16x20
  Entranceway Altar, Near Lenox Avenue, Manhattan, 1990, 16x20
  Lobby Message, Saint Nicholas Avenue near West 116th Street, Manhattan, 1992, 24x20
  Paradise, Bedford-Stuyvesant, Brooklyn, 2000, 24x20
  Pierhula Hair Salon, 13rd Avenue and 77th Street, Brooklyn, 2005, 20x24; Universal Church of the Kingdom of God, Longwood, The Bronx, 2001, 20x24
  Jesus Saves Memorial Gates Avenue near Nostrand Avenue, Brooklyn, 2001, 30x40
  Pedro's Car, Warren Street near 3rd Avenue, Brooklyn, 1998, 30x40